hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jared
michaelski and this podcast I help
coaches trainers and mentors scale their
businesses and make millions of dollars
online using the strategies that I've
learned over the last 20 years of
working with some of the top mentors in
the world and scaling multiple coaching
businesses to over 20 million dollars
and so what I want to talk to you about
is
how to never run out of content to
create and how to actually create killer
content because right there's a
difference between just
run-of-the-mill like content for the
sake of content but then there's also
just being able to have amazing content
that impacts people that helps people
and so how do you bring that balance
personally I don't think content just
for the sake of content is really worth
it and I've always had a standard
of creating a Killer level of content
um people have always asked me what's
your methodology for doing that and it's
really simple is I just listen to what
people ask
I just listened to what are their
problems and then I teach Solutions I if
I don't know the solution that I want to
create a Content full piece of content
for I will learn it for instance I've
had people for a long time asking me you
know how do you manage your time to be
honest
I
uh have a belief that I'm working
through that I'm not really the best at
time management but the truth is the
evidence shows otherwise that I actually
am pretty good at time management and
that I actually get a lot done and I'm
actually very efficient so what I'm
learning is because I don't feel super
confident in teaching that topic just
yet I teach small aspects of it over
time to people whether it be on my
social media
whether it be to my groups or my
podcasts so here's what my methodology
is for teaching killer content first off
is I will usually use my podcast
and my social media content
when I don't have it fully refined
and it's not quite ready yet to package
as a course or put together as a
training because I mean to be honest
when I record a podcast episode like
this while I stand behind everything
that I've said on my podcast and I
reserve the right to change my mind at
any time I have changed my mind on some
of the things that I've said in Old
podcasts
um I don't
put a lot of weight
into
like considering what I'm going to say
for a podcast episode for instance this
episode we had a lady uh Jacqueline in
our
uh coaching group asked me this question
I was like you know what
it's a really good topic and I might
make a course on it and I was like you
know what I should make that this week's
podcast episode so what I did was I just
kind of
went around and I thought okay what
would I want to teach people what are
some of the main aspects of
teaching this to people so the so the
first starting point is know your
audience
who are you creating content towards
all content creation starts with knowing
who you're actually talking to and what
are their problems what are their goals
what do they want to learn
the goal of content is never for you to
try to look smart I don't make my
content for you to think nice things
about me at all
um in fact I have a lot of people who
think nasty things about me because my
content is not as refined as other
people
um but the ones that really resonate
with my content they love it and I I get
rave reviews so I'm gonna keep doing
what I do
part of my methodology is I don't take
content creation that seriously
I focus on one specific type of person
what is their problem sometimes I might
even focus on one person like right now
I'm just imagining that I'm
teaching this to Jacqueline and a few
other clients that we have in our group
that are similar to her that want to
know my methodology for making content
okay and so but then
I look at okay what is it what is a
question
that that person has asked me
and I really focus specifically on not
what do I want to teach people
sometimes I'll do that
but rather what
do these people want to learn from me
what are they actually asking me about
as I create
mechanisms and opportunities in my
community where people get to ask me
questions
where they get to ask me what they want
to learn
and the community actually tells me what
they want me to create content about
and so that's one of the first things is
know your audience and then create
mechanisms where people can actually
tell you and ask you what they want to
learn
now
this is where mindset comes in and I'm
telling you content creation almost
everything when it comes to
this business is it all links back to
mindset but
here's a big one you don't need to have
all the answers you don't need to know
everything
when you can grasp the fact that it's
okay to not have all the answers
that okay
just because somebody asks you
a question if you don't know the answer
that like I gotta I asked I get asked a
ton of questions I have taxes
and corporate structure
and legal matters that I am not
qualified to answer
uh nor do I
like legally want to answer and so I
just tell people like that's not my Lane
I don't have the answers to those
questions you need to talk to an
attorney about that
and so be okay with not having the
answers
and then focus on what are the stuff
that you
particularly
do know information about okay
and so
know your audience
create mechanisms where they can ask you
questions
and then from there
when they ask you questions
I'm walking around so obviously
loud noises from trucks driving by
happens
some people would go back and edit that
out of their podcast
I
personally have no desire to
just because I'm not going to take the
extra hour out of my day to do that
so there's just another
aspect of that
might that piss off some people sure
if that makes them angry oh well
not my problem
and so that's part of the thing is like
when you make content your goal isn't to
please people your goal isn't to
always
give people
and always have the answer and always do
what people want you can't it's
impossible to you're not always going to
have the answer to every question people
ask you you're not always going to have
the answers
to what people need but you might have
an answer
one or two answers you might not have
all five answers that they need but you
might have one or two from your area of
expertise and so just focus on those one
or two that doesn't mean that you're not
good enough
or that your content's not valuable
because you neglected
two or three other topics that people
might want to learn
so understand
that you creating content is
not about you validating your Worth to
other people
gotta get that out of your head
trying to find
self-worth validation from your content
creation
that's one of the biggest things that
will help you because then you'll teach
them a place of confidence the other
thing that I love is that if you can get
yourself into a flow state so for me I
went and walked around my neighborhood
for about 10-15 minutes
and it got me into
the mental state of mind that I needed
to be in to be able to deliver
this content to you very clearly
without needing I don't have a bunch of
notes in front of me
I'm
don't have this perfectly Polished
outline none of my content has actually
built with a perfectly Polished outline
except when it's in my coaching group
now in my coaching group I do kind of
map things out in a more outlined format
because people are making an investment
into me and so I do want that to be in a
more organized fashion but when I'm just
making a podcast or I'm making a piece
of content for my social media
I don't do that I'm more just flow off
the cuff like I'm having a conversation
more conversationally like we're like
we're doing a video chat together it's
kind of my my thought process when I'm
making
social media or podcast content so
knowing your audience
working through
the mental blocks that you might have
such as not having all the answers
fear of failure
it not being perfect enough
there being mistakes they're being edits
they're being background noise
I'd recommend just not even worrying
about any of that stuff to be honest and
actually training your brain
to not because the amount of energy that
I see content creators spending
in
non-content based issues such as making
their content sound perfect look perfect
editing everything outright
the the impact that it has on the bottom
line
for them is so minuscule
that they're they're wasting precious
energy on making their content perfect
when I would actually rather they have a
prolific level of content
now
that's more on the technical aspects of
it like sound and
and all that
how do you actually come up with good
ideas
and this is kind of the the last piece
that I'm going to share this is the one
that a lot of people ask me for how do
you actually come up with good ideas
well I I break down what is the problem
that the person has
what do they want to learn and usually
I'll go to an app like chat GPT
and I'll start to ask chat GPT like what
are some of the problems that somebody
who's trying to do XYZ you might have
what are some solutions that they might
have now I might not have all the
answers to know how to teach about all
those problems or Solutions but I can
make a mental note about two or three of
them and then that gives me ideas
for what to talk about
for what to share with people
I don't ever really use the AI to tell
me what to make my content about but
what I do is I use it to take an idea
that I already have and expand it
so I might have one or two ideas and
then I'll use chat CPT to sort of go on
a little idea journey and pull more
ideas out of me that are already in the
Deep recesses of my brain that are
already deep inside there that maybe I
forgot that I had and then that helps me
really
come up with some great ideas
at the end of the day
the way to actually really come up with
good content and this one is probably
the hardest strategy but the most
important
is
the more content you make
especially I like video and recorded
content because it takes seconds to just
press record
put a piece of content out there and I
didn't have to sit down and write a
whole book I could transcribe this
and I could go through and even create
mental notes and things like that
but
the more content you create
what it'll do is it'll create
a connection to other ideas
so for instance this piece of content
right here this podcast episode it might
create
a branching idea of what are five other
questions that somebody might ask about
creating content like how do you get
into a flow State how do you break past
perfectionism
what type of equipment do you use
personally I'm just using a selfie stick
in my cell phone because I've actually
found that I produce really good content
when I'm just walking around my
neighborhood like this
okay
and so don't get stuck in the weeds of
trying to make your content really good
and perfect
and
they might go against what we started
this episode with you're like hey wait I
thought you were going to show me how to
make killer fire content now you're just
saying make content for the sake of
content
no not necessarily because if you're
actually answering questions that your
audience has
and then you use the AI tools to kind of
Branch out into other ideas and then you
catalyze them asking additional
questions
those ideas that you create content
around are going to be really good
they're going to be
laser focused on what your audience
actually wants to learn and so what I
find is content creation is kind of like
a push-pull relationship where when you
put a piece of content out there
you release it
and then you listen for the feedback
that you get
unfortunately what I found is that
podcast episodes
and social media content have the lowest
level of quality of feedback
and
truthfully
that goes against what most of us want
what most of us desire
what we would like because obviously
it's free it's cheap you can put it out
there
that's why you creating content where
people actually register with their name
and email address
and join you for a virtual event or
maybe they purchase a workshop with you
for seven dollars and you organize
a q a panel
where a group of people asks you
strategic questions about the content
that you taught so you teach
and then you have q a
when you do this
you teach and then have q a
it exponentially increases
the the branching topics that you can
come up with because you're able to
crowdsource
a group of people
in how they receive your content
and so then the feedback loop they give
you feedback for what for how they
received it for how they understood it
and for what they wanted to learn
is whenever I'm creating content
I'm always trying to do it from a
perspective of encouraging a feedback
based conversation where somebody else
is going to respond
to what I'm saying
and then they're going to ask me
questions
as a result
of the content
and so the content isn't just me talking
isn't just me
sharing what's on my mind but it's
actually creating a back and forth
two-way conversation with my audience
see this goes back to what we talked
about when you know your audience and
you're focused on how can I serve them
deliver value to them and actually
answer their questions instead of just
how can I prove how knowledgeable I am
how can I deliver fire content that
sounds great and instead you make it
conversational
around
connecting the dots for another person
you can really take things to the next
level with your content and the last
thing I'm going to share is
listen to
content from others
specifically
I don't listen to content that's related
to what I'm an expert on
because I find that that really
negatively affects my ability to
own my expertise
but what I do listen to content on is
topics that I'm not familiar with
from other great teachers that might be
related to what I'm an expert on for
instance I listen to a lot of personal
development content for my own growth
and then that helps me actually
process my thoughts organize my thoughts
and see how other expert content
creators put their content together so
for instance you listening to this
podcast
could
actually be a way
for you to get better at creating
content I talked about this in a
previous episode about a month ago
is you can borrow the energy from other
experts when you create content you can
borrow the energy from other people
that are great teachers whether it be in
audiobooks or podcast format again hear
me out
I'm not talking about plagiarizing the
exact topic
I almost never listen to content from
other people that teach the same topics
that I teach
because it's just going to get too
muddled and I'll probably end up
accidentally copying what they've said
just because that's just the way that
our brains work but I will borrow from
the energy of teachers that teach on
other topics that I have an interest in
and then I will
learn okay how do they craft their
arguments how do they build
their ideas
and from there I would say okay if they
were going to teach this topic that I'm
an expert on how would they share
this same topic
such as you know how would Ryan holiday
teach
how to create a great content how would
Jocko willink teach how to create great
great content how would David Goggins
teach how to create great content those
are three authors that I like listening
to
their audiobooks
and so I'll listen to their audiobooks
you know how a j Shetty put together
a training on how to make great content
and then from there I'm able to borrow
that energy and how they structure their
trainings and how they structure their
content and filter in my own unique
topic while learning from how these
other experts have done it learning from
the best allows you to actually borrow
the energy from other people and use it
as a model and a template for your own
content
and it might even unlock unique
questions that you never thought to ask
which then will spark ideas and this is
such a huge part of it it'll spark ideas
that you never thought might affect your
audience and then you could even bring
other topics
from other areas other practices into
your coaching program or your training
or your podcast or your content
and so these are just a few strategies
that I've used
to make great content to never run out
of ideas for Content creation
we're really utilizing chat CPT a lot
now
to where what I might do to create good
content is I'll just go for a walk
around my neighborhood I'll take some
notes
I'll write them down on my phone
and then I'll put it into chat GPT and
we're doing a training in my group
called the chat CPT Prompt Academy but
one of the commands that I ask it is
take these notes I'm just got bulleted
notes that I write down like
you know perfectionism
um
listening to other people's podcasts the
basically the stuff that I just talked
about in this episode and I'll tell chat
CPT okay write out and map out
a talk with time stamps that takes these
topics and shares about how to create
great content and it will literally map
that out for me and then if I don't like
what it is I say okay remove that part
add this part into there and that's
actually how I put together this podcast
episode as I actually mapped it out that
way I went for a walk for about 20
minutes and I mapped out some of the
topics that I wanted to share with you
and then the AI was actually allowed me
to actually put it together in a
formatted way to help you now there were
five other topics that it brought up I
didn't want to teach on those but I
taught them the ones that actually had
expertise in and that's how this podcast
episode was generated and that's how I'm
coming up with new ideas for content for
you by implementing both AI as well as
the feedback loop for my clients to
create better content and you can as
well grow your life we'll talk soon
[Music]